<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>EU Integration on Diogo Ferrari</title>
    <link>www.diogoferrari.com/tags/eu-integration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in EU Integration on Diogo Ferrari</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 23:27:44 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="www.diogoferrari.com/tags/eu-integration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Redistributive Attitudes and the Politics of Integration</title>
      <link>www.diogoferrari.com/research/decentralization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 23:27:44 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.diogoferrari.com/research/decentralization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;www.diogoferrari.com/img/centralization.png&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; style=&#34;padding-right: 10px;&#34;&gt; The decision of the UK to leave the EU has demonstrated the relevance of public opinion about integration, as well as the consequences of that decision. Classical theories about public preferences for allocation of political authority in multilevel polities emphasize the role of economic conditions, identity, and nationalist/regionalist values. In the EU, immigration has played a big role on public attitudes. In this project, I evaluate how attitudes about decentralization of political authority are affected by informational shortcuts and perceptions about the economy, inequality, and demand of different groups for welfare policies. In a survey experiment conducted in Brazil, one of the largest federations in the world, I found that people, particularly from the middle class, tend to believe that demand for redistribution actually leads to an increase in welfare state efforts. People act as if the classical Meltzer and Richard mechanism worked. That believe increases the demand for decentralization among the middle and affluent classes if they receive information that there is more demand for redistribution under centralization/integration of social policies. Moreover, perceptions about demand for redistribution affects support for welfare policies, and information about welfare demand alter those preferences. Depending on ideology, high income people who oppose redistribution tend to take more extreme positions when they are informed that demand for welfare is higher than they initially thought. Here is the list of current working papers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public Policy Preferences, Redistribution, and Support for Welfare Integration in Multilevel Polities: a Survey Experiment in Brazil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preference for Redistribution by Policy Area&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Information about Inequality and Support for Redistribution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
