<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Diogo Ferrari</title>
    <link>www.diogoferrari.com/authors/admin/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Diogo Ferrari</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	    <atom:link href="www.diogoferrari.com/authors/admin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>www.diogoferrari.com/authors/admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.diogoferrari.com/authors/admin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;
Welcome to my website! I am a &lt;b&gt;political methodologist&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;comparativist&lt;/b&gt; with expertise in OECD and Latin America countries. My research interests lie on the intersection of political methodology, micro- and macro-foundations political behavior, and the comparative political economy of distributive politics. My work is published or forthcoming at a number of journals, including &lt;i&gt;Political Analysis&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Publius&lt;/i&gt;. You can find a sample of my published and current working papers &lt;a href=&#34;www.diogoferrari.com/publication/&#34;&gt;here&lt;a&gt;.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;

My research in political methodology focuses on machine learning, semi-parametric Bayesian statistics, and computational methods. In particular, I have worked with hierarchical semi-parametric models for density estimation and to deal with latent interactive effects in experimental and observational studies in comparative analyses. See more details &lt;a href=&#34;www.diogoferrari.com/research/&#34;&gt;here&lt;a&gt;.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;

Theoretically, I combine political sociology and political economy approaches to study the micro- and macro-foundation of political behavior. I am interested in understanding how socioeconomic positions shape perceptions about the socioeconomic environment and the normative opinions about economic inequality, social inclusion, and welfare policy. I have conducted national surveys and survey experiments to evaluate how information about the state of the economy, causes of inequality, and demand of different groups for redistribution impact attitudes about welfare policies and political integration. See my &lt;a href=&#34;www.diogoferrari.com/research/&#34;&gt;research&lt;a&gt; page for more details.
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
