<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Diogo Ferrari</title>
    <link>https://DiogoFerrari.github.io/authors/admin/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Diogo Ferrari</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://DiogoFerrari.github.io/authors/admin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://DiogoFerrari.github.io/authors/admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://DiogoFerrari.github.io/authors/admin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;
Welcome to my website! I am a &lt;b&gt;political methodologist&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;comparativist&lt;/b&gt; with expertise in OECD and Latin America countries. My research interests lie on the intersection of political economy, political methodology, and the micro- and macro-foundations political behavior. You can find a sample of my published and current working papers &lt;a href=&#34;https://DiogoFerrari.github.io/publication/&#34;&gt;here&lt;a&gt;.

&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;

Theoretically, I combine political economy, political sociology, and social cognition approaches to study the formation of political preferences. My research investigates the connections between people&#39;s socioeconomic conditions, &lt;i&gt;cognitive perceptions&lt;/i&gt; about the socioeconomic environment, and political opinions. I have conducted national surveys and survey experiments to investigate how different groups react to information about the causes of inequality, state of the economy, and social demand for redistribution. See my &lt;a href=&#34;https://DiogoFerrari.github.io/research/&#34;&gt;research&lt;a&gt; page for more details.

&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;

My research in political methodology focuses on machine learning, Bayesian statistics, computational methods, and causal inference. I investigate how machine learning approaches can help to overcome methodological challenges in comparative politics. In particular, I have worked with Bayesian models to estimate latent interactive effects in experimental and observational studies in quantitative political analyses. See more details &lt;a href=&#34;https://DiogoFerrari.github.io/research/npb/&#34;&gt;here&lt;a&gt;.


&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
